Wizards just dropped a surprise
Christmas spoiler on us and it also just
confirmed which one of our favorite
Planeswalkers isn't getting completed
let's take a look at kaito dancing
Shadow kaito is a full Mana dimir
Planeswalker that has a static ability
that says whenever one or more creatures
you control deal combat damage to a
player you may return one of them to its
owner's hand if you do you may activate
loyalty abilities of kaito twice this
turn rather than only once his plus one
says up to one target creature can't
attack or block until your next turn
he has a zero loyalty ability that
simply draws a card
and he foregoes an ultimate ability for
a minus two that says create a 2-2
colorless drone artifact creature token
with death touch and whenever this
creature leaves the battlefield each
opponent loses to life and you gain two
life
so right off the bat that static seems
really good I wonder if there's going to
be a card that loves it when creatures
with awesome enter the battlefield
abilities get cast over and over again
hmm I'll have to sit and think on that
one
let's talk about that plus one which I
think is amazing we can prevent a
creature from blocking attack with a
creature return it to our hand and then
activate kaito again to either prevent
another creature from attacking or
blocking which is probably only relevant
in multiplayer or we can just draw a
card or create a 2-2 death toucher that
is both amazing on offense as well as
defense
I don't think this kaito is the best
four minor Planeswalker we've ever seen
but the way Demir decks generally try to
win is by scoring small advantages over
your opponent and staying alive which
kaito offers all of that
also the immediate deck this seems to
slot right into is rogues rogues
generally have flash or are cheap enough
that if they're bounced you can just
play them again
plus there's Thieves Guild enforcer who
just loves it when Rogues enter the
battlefield
what do you guys think is this Commander
playable let me know down in the
comments down below